<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog By BlackPirateX</title>
    <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog By BlackPirateX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:46:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.blackpiratex.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Website Update #1</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/website-update-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:46:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/website-update-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have visited my this blog before,(and can remember it) you can clearly see the difference. This blog is now simpler. I like it. Hope you  like it too. As I am going to get busy with my life, I hope I would stick with this theme for very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-this-website-is-made&#34;&gt;How this website is made&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for creating this website. Hugo is  great. I am loving it. Earlier also I was using Hugo, but that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about it, so I used a ready made theme for my website. This time the theme is mine. That is why it is so minimal. This theme uses only HTML and little bit of CSS, I would tweak as time goes on.  The inspiration came from &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz&#34;&gt;Luke Smith&lt;/a&gt;, in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ZFL09qhKi5I/&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; he explained things about hugo, which has helped me a lot. So I made this. I knew that I was going to make my own theme someday, beacuse I do not like those available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I learn more about creating hugo themes, or actually how to use hugo, I shall also make new theme for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gallery.blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt; website. It looks good, but it is slow. I would try to make it javascript free. Right now it uses so much javascript which makes it slow. I know that Hugo can compress images so I need to figure those things out before I move my gallery website to custom made theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suggestions&#34;&gt;Suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would definitely love to get some feedback about how to improve my website. You can send me email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt; regarding this. If you think everything is right, give me few opinions about these -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shall I add comments using github issues?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark mode?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Doesn&#39;t Like Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/fedora-doesnt-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 14:54:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/fedora-doesnt-like-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening lots of good things about fedora, I wanted to give it a try. I was previously using &lt;a href=&#34;https://archcraft.io/&#34;&gt;Archcraft&lt;/a&gt;, but recently it started to give me few errors. Dolphin won&amp;rsquo;t start for some reason. Same problem with OBS Studio also. I can live without dolphin, but needed obs studio. I got an workaround and used ffmpeg to record screen, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as obs studio. So I decided to distro-hop like any rational person would (I hope).
I flashed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ventoy.net/en/index.html&#34;&gt;ventoy&lt;/a&gt; on my Samsung Pen Drive and copied the &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/en/workstation/&#34;&gt;Fedora workstation&lt;/a&gt; iso file to the pen drive.Installation process went fairly smoothly, I am going to dual boot fedora and windows alongside, so had to do manual partitioning. After booting up I did a system update and installed all the softwares I needed. Everything is working just fine, as expected. After using it for more than a week a few problems started to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gnome-shell-is-crashing&#34;&gt;gnome-shell is crashing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system would become unresponsive from time to time and gnome-shell will crash multiple times while using my laptop. I think it maybe is becuase of some gnome extensions, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much research. My experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t as smooth as I was expecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;laggy-video-playback-in-all-web-browser&#34;&gt;Laggy video playback in all web browser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably the most annoying of all the problems I have encountered. Videos will get stuck fruquently while playing, it woun&amp;rsquo;t be stuck for long, but enough to notice it. I tried changing video quality to 720p still didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I have intel i7 9th gen, so I do not think this has anything to do with my hardware. This problem happens in both firefox and chromium. The lag is present on youtube and also on curiosity stream. This is the two websites that I checked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-availablity&#34;&gt;Software Availablity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss AUR, it is just so good. One command and your apps are installed. Fedora has good collection of softwares, But that one or two niche apps that I use are pain in the ass to install. For example I tried installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.downloadhelper.net/install-coapp&#34;&gt;VideoDownloadHelper companion app&lt;/a&gt; but it won&amp;rsquo;t install for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am too lazy to fix all these errors, so here goes my rant. Archcraft is better distro for me. I miss bspwm. So switched back from fedora to archcraft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplelogin - Best Way to Manage Your Emails</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/simplelogin-best-way-to-manage-your-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 19:31:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/simplelogin-best-way-to-manage-your-emails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SimpleLogin is a email aliasing service. Which basically means you can create as many emails as you want* and all those emails would land on single inbox. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using SimpleLogin for over a year now. Here&amp;rsquo;s my evaluation of the service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-use-case&#34;&gt;My Use Case&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who cares about privacy, and had personal emails leaked in data breach previously, I treat emails just like my passwords. I don&amp;rsquo;t want fifty different companies to know my email address just so they can send me marketing emails. Also if you use same email everywhere its pretty easy to stalk you online. Anyone who has your email address would be able to know if you use (or have account) certain website. I don&amp;rsquo;t want others to know which website I visit or which website I have an
account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another use case for me is the ability to add my own custom domain in their premium plan. It is better than any other method of hosting email on your own domain. You get unlimited email address, unlimited domains, ability to turn on catch all,  you can even use regex while creating emails using catch all. All the emails I recieve from different website through different email address lands on my protonmail. I can manage my emails from a single place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features-that-i-like&#34;&gt;Features That I like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SimpleLogin is a powerful tool. And probably one of the most feature rich way of managing emails. Here&amp;rsquo;s list of all the features that I like in SimpleLogin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They have apps for all devices that I use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited custom domain on their premium plan, No one that I know of gives unlimited domain for that cheap. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Click Unsubscribe&lt;/strong&gt;: Have you seen those unsubscribe button on gmail? If you have recieved an email which has been forwarded thorugh SimpleLogin you can click that unsubscribe button and simplelogin would disable that alias for you. Pretty handy right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability To import and export&lt;/strong&gt;: Simplelogin lets you to export all your aliases created with your domain. That means in future if I need to move away from simplelogin it would be much easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to use RegEx while creating emails with catch all&lt;/strong&gt;: This means you can make a complex pattern that only you would know, and new emails would be created when that pattern matches only. It is useful if you are worried about spam when enabling catch all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to use PGP&lt;/strong&gt;: You can enable pgp to your mailbox. all incoming and outgoing emails would be encrypted using pgp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to block single email address&lt;/strong&gt;: If there is one guy spamming you and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to disable the alias for some reason, you can block that email address in simplelogin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is some of the features of simplelogin that I use everyday. It has made my life a lot easier, I can reach inbox zero easily. Also now I do not worry about spam when giving out my email to some shady websites. I love SimpleLogin and going to continue using it. If you have never used simplelogin, I urge you to try it out first. Their free plan is very generous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Degoogled Phone Isn&#39;t as Hard as You Might Think</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/using-degoogled-phone-isnt-as-hard-as-you-might-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 10:27:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/using-degoogled-phone-isnt-as-hard-as-you-might-think/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-degoogled-phone&#34;&gt;What is a degoogled phone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanilla Android is &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/FOSS/&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/a&gt; (Free and OpenSource Software), but the android that you get preinstalled in most phones isn&amp;rsquo;t completely FOSS. It has a blackbox, which is called Google Play Services. A lot of android apps and all google apps relies on this. Sure it provides features like instant notification, but privacy is a nightmare. Degoogling a phone means removing this blackbox, by installing a different flavour of Android which doesn&amp;rsquo;t ship with Google Play Services by default.  LineageOs is a popular example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-did-it&#34;&gt;Why I did it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy!! That&amp;rsquo;s the major reason. But I get some extra advantages like better battery backup, zero notifications etc. (See below for all the advantages / disadvantages).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-did-it&#34;&gt;How I did it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I own two phones. The phone I used for degoogling is Redmi K20 pro, (indian version).
I installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://octavi-os.com/&#34;&gt;Octavi Os&lt;/a&gt;. It is very very feature rich and customisable. In my ecperience it is very stable. It has both gapps (with Google Play Services) and vanilla (without Google Play Servuces) version. I went with vahttps://calyxos.org/nilla version.
(I didn&amp;rsquo;t go with &lt;a href=&#34;https://e.foundation/e-os/&#34;&gt;E Os&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://grapheneos.org/&#34;&gt;Graphene Os&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://calyxos.org/&#34;&gt;Calayx Os&lt;/a&gt; simply because my device does not supports it.) After flashing vanilla version you have a choice to flash gapps or not, and becuase I am trying to degoogle my phone, I am not going to flash gapps. The vanilla version does not comes with any web browser out of the box. So connected my phone to my laptop through usb and transffered &lt;a href=&#34;https://bromite.org&#34;&gt;Bromite&lt;/a&gt;. At this point my phone is very much ready to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apps-that-i-use&#34;&gt;Apps that I use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to stick with &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/FOSS/&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/a&gt; (Free and OpenSource Software) apps as much as possible. My main source of apps is &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt; along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://auroraoss.com/&#34;&gt;Aurora Store&lt;/a&gt; (For those apps which are not avilable on Fdroid). I have added few extra F-Droid repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of all the apps that are currently installed on my device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34;&gt;Brave Browser&lt;/a&gt; - My main browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bromite.org&#34;&gt;Bromite&lt;/a&gt; - Secondary Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox NIghtly&lt;/a&gt; - I have it installed because I was using it previously, but do not use it now. Might uninstall later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt; - Opensource Password Manager with cross device syncing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.simplemobiletools.com/&#34;&gt;Simple Mpbile Tools&lt;/a&gt; - It&amp;rsquo;s not a single app, but rather a collection of apps. I currently use their &lt;strong&gt;Calculator, Clock, Contacts, Draw, Gallery, Keyboard, SMS Messenger, Thank You, Voice Recorder&lt;/strong&gt; apps. I would very much like to use their &lt;strong&gt;Phone&lt;/strong&gt; app, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you turn of speaker while calling. The problem with their Music Player app is that it doesnt let to scrobble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GrapheneOS/Camera&#34;&gt;Graphene Os Camera&lt;/a&gt; - Because of no google play services support, normal gcam mod does not work. This camera app is very simple and gets the job done. &lt;em&gt;They even have QR reader built into it, yay!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.davx5.com/&#34;&gt;DAVx5&lt;/a&gt; - I use this app to sync my contacts using &lt;a href=&#34;https://fruux.com/&#34;&gt;Fruux&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.tachibana.downloader/&#34;&gt;Download Navi&lt;/a&gt; - It is my primary download manager. Although I use 1DM from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://element.io/get-started&#34;&gt;Element&lt;/a&gt; - It is my Matrix client. I may change it later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/de.marmaro.krt.ffupdater/&#34;&gt;FFUpdater&lt;/a&gt; - This app is used to update all my web browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jarnedemeulemeester/findroid&#34;&gt;Findroid&lt;/a&gt; - My Jellyfin client, Avilable on F-Droid through Izzydroid repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yang991178/fluent-reader&#34;&gt;Fluent Reader&lt;/a&gt; - My RSS reader app. Probably the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; looking RSS reader app for Android. I use it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Infinity&lt;/a&gt; - This is a reddit client. It is opensource and has decent amount of features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.chooloo.www.koler&#34;&gt;Koler&lt;/a&gt; - Opensource Dialer app with minimal features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/&#34;&gt;LetterBoxD&lt;/a&gt; - I use it to track movies that I have watched and find new movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/proninyaroslav/libretorrent&#34;&gt;Libretorrent&lt;/a&gt; - I don&amp;rsquo;t do torrenting much on my phone, but have it on my phone, just in case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adobe.lrmobile&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Adobe Lightroom&lt;/a&gt; - Wish there was a good opensource alternative for this. I like lightroom because you can download presets and apply it without having to do the hard work by yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org/apps&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; - Mastodon official client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mixplorer.com/&#34;&gt;Mixplorar&lt;/a&gt; - A file manager. It is probably the &lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt; file manager for android. Has built in tabs support, ability to add almost any cloud storage etc, (I should probably make a post about this app). It is not opensource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mpv-android/mpv-android&#34;&gt;mpv&lt;/a&gt; - It is my alternative video player. sometimes use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nekogram.app/&#34;&gt;Nekogram&lt;/a&gt; - Opensource telegram app. I was previously using Plus messanger, but now starting to switch to nekogram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.telegram.plus&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Plus Messanger&lt;/a&gt; - Telegram features with extra features, closed source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TeamNewPipe/NewPipe&#34;&gt;NewPipe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/polymorphicshade/NewPipe/&#34;&gt;NewPipe x Sponsorblock&lt;/a&gt; - I was planning to move away from using official youtube app. Newpipe is a frontend for youtube. It has all the features that I need, but super buggy, non useable for primary youtube app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.github.ashutoshgngwr.noice&#34;&gt;Noice&lt;/a&gt; - Opensource white noise app. Whenever I have trouble getting into sleep I put on my earphones, and try to sleep while listening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kawaiiDango/pScrobbler&#34;&gt;Pano Scrobbler&lt;/a&gt; - Last.fm and libre.fm scrobbler. Opensource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plex.tv/&#34;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt; - Jellyfin is good, but I have a hard time configuring it. So I have plex as alternative. Just wish that plex worked without internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/en/&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; - My read later app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://protonapps.com/&#34;&gt;Proton Apps&lt;/a&gt; - I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonvpn.com&#34;&gt;ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.protonmail.com/&#34;&gt;Proton Calender&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raindrop.io&#34;&gt;Raindrop&lt;/a&gt; - Bookmark manager. Opensource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io&#34;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; - A service that lets you organize all your highlights from different places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=grape.k.readwiseapp&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Readwise WIdget&lt;/a&gt; - A simple app that lets you add an widget to your home screen which shows your readwise highlights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topjohnwu/Magisk&#34;&gt;Magisk&lt;/a&gt; - Rooting app for android. Opensource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.michaldrabik.showly2&#34;&gt;Showly&lt;/a&gt; - It is a tv show tracker which syncs with trakt.tv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io&#34;&gt;SimpleLogin&lt;/a&gt; - It is an email aliasing service that lets you create aliases for each and every website. I also use this service to host email on my domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simplenote.com&#34;&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt; - A note taking app focuused on simplicity. I use it to write something down quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://snapdrop.net&#34;&gt;Snapdrop&lt;/a&gt; - Airdrop like app for android. Open Source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spotify.com&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; - My music streaming app of choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.swiftapps.swiftbackup&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Swift Backup&lt;/a&gt; - This is probably one of the first apps that I would install on any new device. It lets you to take backup of your apps with app data and sync it to the cloud. Since I change roms quiute often it is useful for me to be able to restore any app in its current state. Closed source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ticktick.com/&#34;&gt;Tick Tick&lt;/a&gt; - Todo list app. Closed Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://torproject.org&#34;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt; - This doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tutanota.com&#34;&gt;Tutanota&lt;/a&gt; - Email client for tutanota.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AdrienPoupa/VinylMusicPlayer&#34;&gt;Vinyl&lt;/a&gt; - Offline music player to play my mp3s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.videolan.org/vlc/&#34;&gt;VLC&lt;/a&gt; - Open source feature rich video player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://whatsapp.com&#34;&gt;WhatsApp &amp;amp; WhatsApp Business&lt;/a&gt; - Main text messaging app for my phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vancedapp.com&#34;&gt;Youtube Vanced&lt;/a&gt; - Even though vanced has been discontinued it still works so I would keep using it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is few advantages of using a degoogled phone. The obvious one is privacy. While it is true that using a degoogled phone makes you more private from google, it has other advantages too. Your battery backup would be excellent. Around 9-10 hours in single charge for a 4000mAh battery. I have noticed less heating while using degoogled phone. Phone is also faster than it outherwise be with google apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on how much you are into google ecosystem disadvantages can be almost none or very much. For me I only use google photos and youtube. Google photos does not work obviously, but you can youtube get working with youtube vanced. As for google photos I have decided to keep it locally and then take backup to my laptop every month or so. Google maps does not work at all. (even with microg I cannot get it working properly). Other than these few problems there is nothing that effects me.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about all the other problems that you are likely to face if you are using android with Google Play Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications might not work if its dependent on Google Play Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Google Play Store, that means all your purchases won&amp;rsquo;t work. (You can get them working by using microg).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gcam does not work out of the box. There is an app that can fix this issue hopefully but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banking apps won&amp;rsquo;t work. You can get them work with microg and magisk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety net won&amp;rsquo;t pass. You can make them pass with magisk and microg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are used to use &amp;lsquo;Login with Google&amp;rsquo; you would either have to set a password for that app or create new account with email and password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of apps would even refuse to open if you don&amp;rsquo;t have google play services installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its disadvantages you might want to try degoogling your phone, at least once and see if its going to work for you or not. If you are using propietory software most of the times, maybe you might wanna switch to FOSS alternatives. Most FOSS apps are not relient on Google Play Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most fundamental things like calling or texting works without any hiccups. It is very much possible to live with a degoogle phone and avoid big tech as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexual Reproduction in Flowering Plants</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/sexual-reproduction-in-flowering-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/sexual-reproduction-in-flowering-plants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pre-fertilisation-events-and-structures&#34;&gt;Pre-Fertilisation Events and Structures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several hormonal and structural changes happen which lead to the differentiation and further devlopment of &lt;strong&gt;floral primordium&lt;/strong&gt; before flower in seen on a plant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflorecences are formed which bears the floral bud and then the flowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structures of a flower&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Androecium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the male reproductive organ of the flower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Androecium consists of &lt;strong&gt;stamens&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number and length of stamens are variable in different species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stamen has two parts.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anther&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the bilobed structure at the terminal of the stamen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;filament&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the long and slender stalk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gynoecium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the female reproductive organ of the flower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It consists of pistil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If gynoecium consists of one pistil it is called &lt;strong&gt;monocarpellary&lt;/strong&gt;. If it consists of more than one then it is called &lt;strong&gt;multicarpellary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each pistil consists of three structures.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stigma&lt;/strong&gt; → It is where the pollen grains are landed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Style&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the long slender part beneath the stigma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ovary&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the basal bulged part.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the ovary there is &lt;strong&gt;ovarian cavity (locule).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;placenta is located in the ovarian cavity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Megasporongia&lt;/strong&gt; arise from the placenta. Which are commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Ovules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of ovules in an ovary can be &lt;strong&gt;one(wheat, paddy, mango)&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;multiple (papaya, water melon, orchids)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;stamen-microsporongium-and-pollen-grain&#34;&gt;Stamen, Microsporongium and pollen Grain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A typical angiosperm stamen is &lt;strong&gt;bilobed and dithecous&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A longitudinal groove runs lengthwise seperating the theca.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The anther is a &lt;strong&gt;tetragonial structure consisting four microsporongia in each four corners&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsporongium&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsporongium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It devlops further to make pollen sacs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are packed with pollen grains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In transverse section a typical microsporongia appears to be &lt;strong&gt;near circular in outline&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a four layer of walls srrounding it. From outside to inside it those are
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epidermis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endothecium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;middle layer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tapetum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outermost three layers (epidermis, endothecium, middle layer) helps in protection and dehiscence of anther to release the pollen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tapetum nourishes the pollen grains&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tapetum has &lt;strong&gt;dense cytoplasm and usually have more than one neucleus&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When anther is young compactly arranged homogenous tissues occupies the middle of the microsporongium, these cells are called &lt;strong&gt;sporogenous tissue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsporogenesis&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsporogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each microsporongium has lots of microspore mother cells/pollen mother cell (MMC/PMC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each cells of the sporongenous tissue undergo miotic division to form four cells which together are called Microspore Trtrad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the anther dehydrates and matures they disassociate from each other and each make pollen grain or microspore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pollen-grain&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pollen Grain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each pollen grains are male gametophyte.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the yellowish powdery thing that sticks on your finger when you touch the anther of hibbiscus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollen grains are &lt;strong&gt;generally spherical, and has a diameter of about 25-50 micrometers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has has prominent two layered wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the outermost layer of the pollen grain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is made up of &lt;strong&gt;sporopollenin which is a fatty substance.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is one of the most resistant organic material known. It can withstand high temparature and acid and alkali. No engyme can degrade sporopollenin so far known.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
3. It has prominent &lt;strong&gt;apertures which which are called germ pores&lt;/strong&gt;, where sporopollenin is absent.
4. germ pores are required for fertilisation.
5. Pollen grains are &lt;strong&gt;well preserved as fossils because of this sporopollenin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intine&lt;/strong&gt;
1. It is under the extine.
2. It is a thin continious layer &lt;strong&gt;made up of cellulose and pectin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When pollen grains mature it contains two cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vegitative Cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is bigger in size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has &lt;strong&gt;abundunt food reserve&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necleus is irregularly shaped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative Cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is smaller in size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spindle shaped&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dense cytoplasm and a necleus&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollen grains &lt;strong&gt;can cause allergic reactions, leading to chronic repiratory disorder like, asthma, bronchitis etc&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parthenium or carrot grass that came into india as a contaminent with imported wheat, is cause of pollen allergy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Reproduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/human-reproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 20:23:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/human-reproduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;male-reproductive-organ&#34;&gt;Male Reproductive Organ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male reproductive organs consists of testes, accesssory glands, glands and external genetitalia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male reproductive system is located in pelvic region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one pair of testes which is situated outside the human body within a pouch called scrotum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrotum has lower temparature than the body (2-2.5 degree celcius less)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This lower temparature is necessuary for spermatogenesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testis is oval in shape 4-5cm in length and 2-3 cm in width.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testes has 250 compartments which are called testicular lobules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each testicular lobules contains 2-3 seminiferous tubules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seminiferous tubules has two types of cells
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;germ cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sertoli cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germ cells undergo miotic divisions to produce sperms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sertoli cells mostly provide nutritions to germ cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the region outside the seminiferous tubules is called interstitial space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is full with blood vessels and cells found here are called interstitial cells or &lt;strong&gt;Laydig Cells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laydig cells secrete and synthesis testicular hormones called androgens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure-of-male-reproductive-accessory-ducts&#34;&gt;Structure of Male reproductive accessory ducts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seminiferous tubules opens into rete testis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rete testis opens into &lt;strong&gt;Vasa Efferentia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vasa Efferentia opens into &lt;strong&gt;Epididymis&lt;/strong&gt; which is located at the posterior of the testes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epididymis opens into &lt;strong&gt;Vasa Deferens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasa Deferens&lt;/strong&gt; ascends to the abdomen and loops over the urinary bladder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It recieves a duct from seminal vesicle and opens into urethra as ejaculatory duct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Urethra originates from urinary bladder and ends in the external opening of penis called &lt;strong&gt;Urethral meatus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penis is external genitilia of male, it is made up of special tissue which helps in erection for insemination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enlarged end of the penis is called glans penis and it is covered by foreskin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male accessory glands include &lt;strong&gt;paired seminal vesicle&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;one prostate gland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;a pair of bulbourethral glands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secretions of these makes &lt;strong&gt;Seminal plasma&lt;/strong&gt; which is rich in &lt;strong&gt;fructose, calcium.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-female-reproductive-system&#34;&gt;The Female Reproductive System&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The feamle reproductive system consists of &lt;strong&gt;a pair of ovaries,  a pair of oviducts (fallopian tubes), utereus, cervix, vagina, and external genetilia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ovaries are located two sides of the utereus of lower abdomen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ovaries forms ovum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallopian tubes extends from the periphery of the ovary to the utereus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fallopian tubes are 10-12 cm long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The funnel shaped thing near ovaries are called &lt;strong&gt;Infundibulum&lt;/strong&gt; which has finger-like projections called &lt;strong&gt;fimbrie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The part after infundibulum is called ampulla, it is wider, (this is the place where fertilisation takes place.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The part after ampulla is called isthmus, which connects to the utereus by a narrow lumen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus is called womb. It is shaped as inverted pear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has ligaments attacted to the pelvic region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus opens into vagina by a narrow cervix. i&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cavity of the cervix is called cervical canal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus has three layers.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permetruim&lt;/strong&gt; - External thin membrenous tissue layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myometrium&lt;/strong&gt; - middle thick layer of smooth muscles, exibits strong contractions during childbirth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endometrium&lt;/strong&gt; - inner glandular layer, it undergoes cyclical changes during menstrual cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Female external genitilia consists of &lt;strong&gt;mons pubis, labia majora, labia minora, clitoris, hymen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mons pubis&lt;/strong&gt; is a coushion of fatty tissue covered by skin and pubic hair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;labia majora&lt;/strong&gt; is a fleshy folds of tissue that extends from down the mons pubis and surround the vaginal opening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;labia minora&lt;/strong&gt; is under the labia majora.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clitoris&lt;/strong&gt; is a finger like structure which is located between the joints of two labia minora.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes vagina opening is partially covered by a membrane called &lt;strong&gt;hymen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hymen gets broken during the first intercourse (coitus), but it can also be broken by sudden fall or jolt, or by some sports like horseback riding, cycling etc, or by insertion of vaginal tampon etc. This is why it is not a reliable indicator of virginity or sexual experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;females have two mammary glands, which are called breasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these glands contains glandular tissue and variable amount of fat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the grandular tissue of each breasts is divided into &lt;strong&gt;15-20 mammary lobes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mammary lobes contains clusters of cells called &lt;strong&gt;alveoli&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alveoli&lt;/strong&gt; secretes milk, which is stored inside the cavity (lumen) of alveoli.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alveoli opens into &lt;strong&gt;mammary tubules&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tubules from each lobe gets together and forms &lt;strong&gt;mammary duct.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiple mammary ducts joins the wider mammary ampulla which is connected to the &lt;strong&gt;lactiferous duct&lt;/strong&gt; through which milk is sucked out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search for Perfect Daily Journal App</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:08:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be considered a viable app for my Daily Journal needs it must have following charateristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either end to end encrypted if the app is cloud based or data stays locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross platform. Including Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy way to export for personal backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of lack of privacy at my home, I had moved away from physical pen and paper diaries and moved completely to digital. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to hide something online than trying to hide at my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evernote&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very begining, circa 2017, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; Evernote was good back then. The 60mb that you get in free tier of evernote was more than enough for text based notes. I created a Notebook and used to add the date as title. It wasnt perfect. Writting date each and every day as note title is a tedious task. The search continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-unknown-app&#34;&gt;Some Unknown App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an app from playstore. I dont remember the name.  It was paid but i got it on a deal. Didn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anything. It was okay. Like not much features. Your data is stored locally. Although it had option to sync to dropbox. I used the sync feature. Sadly I dont think the app is alive. I maybe able to find it if I scroll back to my google play purchase history, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have that much patience. Unfortunately all the entries from that app is gone. I dont remember the droobox
account either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daybook&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next app that I used was &lt;a href=&#34;https://daybook.app&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/a&gt; , it was very minimal and decent app. It had lots of feature but free version was kinda limited. Still the UI and simplicity was the reason for using that app. But at the end one thing that put me off was their privacy policy. It was neither end to encrypted nor it had good privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notion&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; and started to love it. Notion had so many great features that I loved. Ability to make templates was one of them. Notion also supports basic markdown.  I remember using notion for like two months before the problems starts to appear.
Notion was online only, that means I cannot write my daily journal if my wifi was off. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen that often, but it was a possibility. Also if I go outside for few days, there would be no gurantee if I would be able to connect to the internet. It also bothered me that notion android app was basically a web app. Which means it was laggy, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel as smooth as native app.  The last thing that made me switch to Standard Notes was bad security and
privacy. Notion also is not end to end encrypted. They don&amp;rsquo;t even offer 2 step verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standard-notes&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://standardnotes.com&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/a&gt; was very good. I used their free version only, but still it was better than all previous apps that I have used. Security and privacy is great. They use end to end encryprion, and yes you cannot recover your password if you have lost it. They had apps for all the platforms. You can lock any particular note with another pin. It has theming support. If you get their premium version you&amp;rsquo;d get access to extensions which extends it&amp;rsquo;s
functionality.  I used it for a very long time before considering to switch.
Their free version is just plain text, nothing else. Sure you can use community made extensions to get markdown editors or different themes, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good. There were also no support for images, I  do not know if images support was avilable on paid plans or not. There were no support for templates. Themes are quite a bit limited on free version. These were the main reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t stick with standard notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joplin&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I was bored I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;. It is also one very good app. It supports templates, there is few options when it comes to themes, it also has plugin support. I used joplin for a good amount of time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it because it has nothing interesting about it. It is opensource and by deafult does not sync to any cloud, (I think they have a paid plan now that lets you to sunc to their cloud). Even though their desktop app was decent
android app sucked. The UI looks so outdated, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all the features that the desktop version has. Android app is also not very smooth. It has the ability to sync to dropbox but the sync is so slow. And if you have enabled end to end encryption through the settings, good luck getting it working properly. Keep in mind that most problems I had with this app is in their android app, beacuse thats what I used to use to write my journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;obsidian&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; is the current app I am using. I absolutely love this app. It uses normal markdown files for each and every note, you can create normal folders inside obsidian and it would show the folders. Because each and individual notes are just simple .md files you can open them using any kind of text editor you prefer. Right now I am using Vim to edit this text. Obsidian is not open source but it can work offline, only time it needs to connect to the internet
is when downloading themes or plugins. Yes it supports themes, and I am pretty sure you can add your own css to obsidian. It also has template feature inbuilt, you can make it even more powerful with plugins. You can link your notes to another notes(Just like Roam Research, but you can only link a particular note and not a paragraph), and you can view a graph view which shows which note is linked with which. It is useful for me in so many cases, and not a lot of apps does that.
Everything is offline in obsidain by default, which may sound like a drawback if you want to sync your data with multiple devices, but it is not. Sure it is not as straightforward as installing an app and logging in, but you can make it work. I personally use DropBox (I would move to nextcloud once I get my nextcloud server running on raspberry pi) to sync my files. In linux and windows you can use the official dropbox app to sync the obsidian folder, and on Android you can use AutoSync
to sync to dropbox.
Obsidian can be very powerful if you want it to be, but it can be simple too. Third party plugins can extend the functionality of the app. &lt;em&gt;Plugins are also supported by their android app!!! How cool is that?&lt;/em&gt;
Obsidian is very good at what it does. But by no means it is perfect. It is bit tricky to set up sync on your devices,(like I have mentioned above) and even if you are able to set it up properly, you might get conflicts. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me because I am used to it at this point but I can see how this would make others annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There  is so many things an app needs to get right before I would use it for long, and yes I may not be the &amp;lsquo;general user&amp;rsquo;, So if you use any of the apps from above tell me what made you stick with it?
I am happy with obsidian as of now and not planning to switch anytime soon. Maybe someday when I learn vim or emacs enough to make obsidian obselete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was last updated on: 27/04/2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Journaling Is Better Than Physical Journaling</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/digital-journaling-is-better-than-physical-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:18:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/digital-journaling-is-better-than-physical-journaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy is better on digital Journalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More customisable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less bulky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to write&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search and Reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;better-privacy&#34;&gt;Better Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A daily journal is probably going to be one of the most private thing in your life. Because I know for a fact that, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how close you are to me I&amp;rsquo;m never going to share my journal with anyone but me.
If you are able to write digitally right way then it is very much possible to have greater privacy than that you&amp;rsquo;d get in physical journal. If you dont live alone, then its possible they can sneak into your journal. Even if I trust that person completely I&amp;rsquo;ll still be more comfortable knowing that he/she cannot access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easy-to-backup&#34;&gt;Easy to backup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not seem like something that is necessary for you, but for me backups are most important part of a journal. If I cannot read my journal entries 10-20 years into the future, then why bother writting it in the first place? Journals are sonething that I want to keep till the day I die.
You might argue that paper will last longer than lets say your hdd or any kind of digital storage, and you are right. But the problem is that in paper it is harder to copy, and maintain. You would to worry about pages turning yellow, different types of insects harming the paper, or worse some kind of disaster happening (like fire, water etc) and ruining your paper. You would be lose everything at once. Yes sure if you want to go to the extra mile you can make a xerox copy of your journals and it would medigate this problem. But it would easily get expensive as time goes on.&lt;br&gt;
On the other hand if you write digitally it would be so much easier to make backups of your journal. You can copy the containing folder and back it up somewhere else. Or if you are using something like &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Notion&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Evernote&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they all have some kind of export method. (You should not be using any writting app anyway which does not let you export your data easily.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;customization&#34;&gt;Customization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is theoratically no limit to how you would customise your journal. If you do not like a certain program you can always move to another, if you are still not satisfied to all the options you can write your own, well it would take time, but it is possible. Or you can use simple markdown files. With any text editors, let it be simple notepad or vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;less-bulky&#34;&gt;Less Bulky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital journals are less bulky, you do not need any significant extra space at your home for digital journals. I have my journals from 2018 written digitally and they are just a few megabytes. Granted I do not write everyday and do not include much medias, (they are mostly plain texts with little bit of formatting here and there), it is still very little amount of files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easier-to-write&#34;&gt;Easier to write&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is significantly easier to write on keyboard than to use pen or paper. There is usually significant speed benifits, and automation, which I&amp;rsquo;ll explain on next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can automate things in your digital journal. If you are someone like me who likes to answer questions in form of Journal (ex: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;What did you do today?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;), you can make a template of your writting software so that everyday when you open your journal you start from your template instead starting form a blank page. Yes theoritically you can do the same on physical paper too, but it is easier digitally, and much much more advanced. I shall write a blog post about it someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ability-to-search-and-reference-back&#34;&gt;Ability to search and reference back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its easier to search a page or a mention of a specific thing on your journal. If you wrie digitally.
You can also reference back your old journals if necessary easily. For example you can have a page that would contain all the days where youn done something X, you can reference that page each time you do the X. I&amp;rsquo;ts bit advanced  stuff, but yes it would be helpful when you look back at the year or the decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical form of journaling has its advantages there is no doubt about that, but personally I prefer Digital ones. The beauty of digital journalism is that it can be as much complex as you want it to be, it can perfectly as you like it. Given that you are comfortable giving your time and energy to it. If you want a place to dump your brain and trying to lower your screen on time, then maybe you would be better off with physical ones, but for most people I think digital journal is much better than physical ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to say about this post, you can email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Wm</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/why-i-love-wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:13:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/why-i-love-wm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WM stands for window manager. It is a alternative to using full blown desktop environment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/window_manager&#34;&gt;More info on ArchWiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently started using WM, first i3 now on openbox. And absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are someone who is used to use normal desktop environment like gnome, kde, xfce or any other &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/desktop_environment&#34;&gt;DE (Desktop Environment)&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest to try out WM.You can start with anyone of those window manager you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with. Setting up wm is easy on fresh arch install so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-can-do-everything-using-keyboard-shortcuts&#34;&gt;You can do everything using keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening windows, closing windows, moving to different workspaces etc, can be done using keyboard shortcuts. It took me few days to get used to use keyboard shortcuts but now i can say it&amp;rsquo;s miles better than using mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-window-doesnt-cover-another&#34;&gt;One window doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover another&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t (by default), and why the hell would you want to keep one window on top of another?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;easily-customizable&#34;&gt;Easily customizable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I open up documentation in one workspace and vim with config file opened in another workspace. Changing everything is as easy as editing a text file. Documentations are mostly gets the job done, but if still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work one quick brave Search or youtube search does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loading-others-configuration&#34;&gt;Loading other&amp;rsquo;s configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna configure everything by myself, so I&amp;rsquo;d go &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/unixporn&#34;&gt;r/unixporn&lt;/a&gt; and load other&amp;rsquo;s configuration. And  &lt;em&gt;voilà&lt;/em&gt; its done. Well in reality I still have to open the config file and tweak here and there, but it&amp;rsquo;s usually &amp;rsquo;less time consuming&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forces-you-to-use-the-terminal&#34;&gt;Forces you to use the terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty new when it comes to Linux. Although terminal doesn&amp;rsquo;t scare me anymore, I sometimes still think using terminal is hard. Using a wm forces me to use terminal when possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;texts--icons&#34;&gt;Texts &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Icons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been a fan of icons, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer simple texts over icons any day. A window manager normally doesn&amp;rsquo;t have icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-minimal-less-distracting-more-productive&#34;&gt;Its minimal, less distracting, more productive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t spend any time trying to arrange my opened tabs. (Suck on that Windows users) I&amp;rsquo;d open a programme because I want to open it, not because I was sitting mindlessly and getting bored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;elitism-feeling&#34;&gt;Elitism Feeling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes with the OS, if you&amp;rsquo;re a Linux user you know what I&amp;rsquo;m taking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still not convinced, I&amp;rsquo;ll suggest you give it a try, take a break from conventional way of managing windows and embrace the new. You can always go back to doing things your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS:&lt;/strong&gt;  I use Arch BTW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have something to say about this post, mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:blackpirate101@protonmail.com&#34;&gt;blackpirate101@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can click above or copy the email address from below.
&lt;code&gt;blackpirate101@protonmail.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Various Password Managers</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/my-experience-with-various-password-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 18:53:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/my-experience-with-various-password-managers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years i have used many password managers. One of the biggest reasons I started using a password manager is not because of the security but rather I wanted a quick way to type my passwords. Also its easy for me to loose track of the websites I have signed up for. Now you may ask why I didn&amp;rsquo;t use something like password manager built in most modern web browser? Well the answer to that question is I wanted all my passwords to sync to different browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting I want to clear some things first. This review is based on my overall experience. I have only android devices and windows and linux. Your mileage may vary if you are on different devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lastpass&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LastPass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros -&amp;gt; There is seriously none. Only reason to use it would be you&amp;rsquo;re into their ecosystem and can&amp;rsquo;t get out, or you have to use it for work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android app is terrible. The UI looks outdated. Android app is filled with trackers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has very serious security flaws throughout the years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LastPass#Security_issues&#34;&gt;More Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free version is unusable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot export your 2fa seeds if you ever plan to move to a new password manager. (Its necessary feature to have if you are planning to future proof your passwords or 2fa seeds.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitwarden&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt; There is lot to love in Bitwarden.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security is flawless. Their apps are open source, You can self host your own instance if you want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy is also top notch. Android apps don&amp;rsquo;t contain any kind of trackers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has wide range of supported devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably the best free version of all the password managers. You would have to pay only if you need document support or want to generate TOTP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons: These might sound like nitpicking.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t like the android app ui. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel modern. It isn&amp;rsquo;t laggy but feels sluggish.&lt;/del&gt;  Update 29/04/2022: I am not bothered by it now, but yes sometimes Bitwarden lags while trying to autofill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their premium version is only 10$ per year, yes its hella cheap, but not in devloping countries. I wish they did regional pricing (I would definitely pay for it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to have an option where I can upload the encrypted data to a cloud drive. Its like self hosting only the data. (1password and enpass can do this.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of document support in free version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1password&#34;&gt;1password&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1.  If you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay for a password manager this can be a great choice.
2. Absolutely a lot of features that you might find useful. For example password history, ability to add any custom field and section to store different types of information.
3. You can choose to store all the encrypted data to your own choice of cloud storage, like dropbox or google drive.
4. There&amp;rsquo;s no trackers in android apps and windows apps.
5. Ability to have multiple vaults,  but Enpass&amp;rsquo;s implementation is better.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot upload documents if you choose to store passwords by yourself (kinda like self hosting but not really) I mean one of the main reason to self host is that you can get document storage as much as you need. Even dropbox free gives 2GB (which can be increased to 18GB) which is much better than 1GB storage that you get in your subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not open source at all. But they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any data breach or anything that I can find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enpass&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enpass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enpass.io/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;
1. Extremely feature rich. It has everything you can ask for in a password manager.
2. It works without any account or without internet connection at all. Although you&amp;rsquo;ll need internet connection to sync across devices which is optional.
3. Ability to have multiple vaults, (1Password has this feature too but in my opinion enpass&amp;rsquo;s implementation is better.)
4. There&amp;rsquo;s no limit of how many data (passwords, documents, notes) you can store.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All apps are closed source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dashlane&#34;&gt;Dashlane&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dashlane.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:-&lt;/strong&gt;
1. The user interface is very simple.
2. Beginner-normie Friendly
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:-&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing is open source. Privacy is meh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features are very limited. Last time I checked they didn&amp;rsquo;t even had option for custom fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Desktop Application, You&amp;rsquo;ll have to use their web app or extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free version doesn&amp;rsquo;t sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keepass&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keepass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keepass.info/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;
I have used keepass only briefly, I have multiple devices, so I need to access my keepass file everywhere, which is not an easy task to do with keepass.
I know that it is achieveable, but it sure is not as straightforward as something like bitwarden or enpass. I tried using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keepassdx.com/&#34;&gt;KeePassDX&lt;/a&gt; with dropbox sync, and it gets conflict so often. So it gets pretty unuseable. I may start using it again once I figure out how to get sync working properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the password managers I have used my favourite would be Bitwarden, Enpass is a close second. If closed source stuff does not bother you and you want extra fatures, you can use Enpass or 1Password. I personally would prefer enpass more than 1Password. Currently as of April 2022 I aPeriod.m using Bitwarden. Earlier I was using enpass, only reason I moved away from enpass is beacuse of it&amp;rsquo;s closed source nature. For something as important as password manager, it should be open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextdns Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/nextdns-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 14:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/nextdns-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-dns&#34;&gt;What is DNS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Domain Name System is a hierarchical and decentralized naming system for computers, services, or other resources connected to the Internet or a private network. It associates various information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-nextdns&#34;&gt;What is NextDNS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is a dns service which lets you block sites at dns level. That means it can block ads and trackers. Which is the main selling point of this service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/img/nextdns-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;nextdns-logo&#34;&gt;
In simpler words it&amp;rsquo;s phone book of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using NextDNS for almost few months now. Yes I&amp;rsquo;ve been using their free plan. Which is more than enough for me. My experience with NextDNS is very positive. Once I set it up and did all the testing it never disappointed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;convenient&#34;&gt;Convenient&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is pretty convinient way to block ads. In privacy section there&amp;rsquo;s option to add well known adblocker blocklist. And it&amp;rsquo;s as easy it gets. After setting up your configuration you can easily change your dns setings in your operating system.
For more setup guide you can scroll down on their website and check their guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-time-setup&#34;&gt;First Time Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up for the first time is easy, but it night be a bit hard for non techie people. At first I was also having trouble finding out how to whitelist certain site. Also if you select all the adblock filters you might have some issues on certain sites. For example in my case my youtube app wasn&amp;rsquo;t recording history. Then I had to disable few adblock list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know NextDNS is pretty secure. They had option for 2step verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy&#34;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default privacy settings are crappy on NextDNS. But the good thing is that they let you change the default settings. By default it logs everything. I recommend you to disable logs and clear logs right now if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it already. Also NextDNS requires an email adress which you can easily fake using temp mail or alias.
In NextDNS you can link IP. Which is not good for privacy so wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using that feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is feature packed. It&amp;rsquo;s like having your own pi hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pi-hole or Pihole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole and optionally a DHCP server, intended for use on a private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In NextDNS you can add different types of blocklist to block ads and trackers. Sadly they won&amp;rsquo;t allow you to choose to add your own blacklist. But in Denylist you can choose to block certain domain but sadly it won&amp;rsquo;t be possible to block a lot of domains at once.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/img/nextdns-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;features&#34;&gt;
Their parental control feature is also awesome. It lets you block popular social media apps and websites in single click. Also there&amp;rsquo;s an option for recreation time which will allow those blocked sites for certain periods of time on certain days of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recreation time: Set a period for each day of the week during which some of the websites, apps, games or categories above will not be blocked — e.g. allow Facebook on Mondays and Tuesdays between 6pm and 8pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also turn on safesearch by default, block age restricted videos on youtube and block bypass methods like vpn. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how effective they&amp;rsquo;re, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have the option.
In analytics section you can see the analytics of that dns. Keep in mind that it only works if you have turned on logs.
NextDNS works on different types of DNS protocol like DNS over HTTPS, DNS over TLS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pricing&#34;&gt;Pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS free version is enough for me, (it gives you 300k dns queries) and also be enough for most people. But they also have paid plans which is a bit expensive where I live. Overall I&amp;rsquo;ll say it&amp;rsquo;s good for most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s looking for dns based adblocking solution NextDNS should be good enough for most of the people. Its convinient to set up (usually takes few mins), easy to manage and their free plan is actually useable. But for people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to trust a central company for all their internet traffic pi hole would be the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>