<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog By BlackPirateX</title>
    <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog By BlackPirateX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>BlackPirateX</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:08:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.blackpiratex.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Search for Perfect Daily Journal App</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:08:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be considered a viable app for my Daily Journal needs it must have following charateristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either end to end encrypted if the app is cloud based or data stays locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross platform. Including Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy way to export for personal backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of lack of privacy at my home, I had moved away from physical pen and paper diaries and moved completely to digital. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to hide something online than trying to hide at my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evernote&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very begining, circa 2017, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; Evernote was good back then. The 60mb that you get in free tier of evernote was more than enough for text based notes. I created a Notebook and used to add the date as title. It wasnt perfect. Writting date each and every day as note title is a tedious task. The search continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-unknown-app&#34;&gt;Some Unknown App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an app from playstore. I dont remember the name.  It was paid but i got it on a deal. Didn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anything. It was okay. Like not much features. Your data is stored locally. Although it had option to sync to dropbox. I used the sync feature. Sadly I dont think the app is alive. I maybe able to find it if I scroll back to my google play purchase history, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have that much patience. Unfortunately all the entries from that app is gone. I dont remember the droobox
account either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daybook&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next app that I used was &lt;a href=&#34;https://daybook.app&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/a&gt; , it was very minimal and decent app. It had lots of feature but free version was kinda limited. Still the UI and simplicity was the reason for using that app. But at the end one thing that put me off was their privacy policy. It was neither end to encrypted nor it had good privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notion&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; and started to love it. Notion had so many great features that I loved. Ability to make templates was one of them. Notion also supports basic markdown.  I remember using notion for like two months before the problems starts to appear.
Notion was online only, that means I cannot write my daily journal if my wifi was off. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen that often, but it was a possibility. Also if I go outside for few days, there would be no gurantee if I would be able to connect to the internet. It also bothered me that notion android app was basically a web app. Which means it was laggy, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel as smooth as native app.  The last thing that made me switch to Standard Notes was bad security and
privacy. Notion also is not end to end encrypted. They don&amp;rsquo;t even offer 2 step verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standard-notes&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://standardnotes.com&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/a&gt; was very good. I used their free version only, but still it was better than all previous apps that I have used. Security and privacy is great. They use end to end encryprion, and yes you cannot recover your password if you have lost it. They had apps for all the platforms. You can lock any particular note with another pin. It has theming support. If you get their premium version you&amp;rsquo;d get access to extensions which extends it&amp;rsquo;s
functionality.  I used it for a very long time before considering to switch.
Their free version is just plain text, nothing else. Sure you can use community made extensions to get markdown editors or different themes, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good. There were also no support for images, I  do not know if images support was avilable on paid plans or not. There were no support for templates. Themes are quite a bit limited on free version. These were the main reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t stick with standard notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joplin&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I was bored I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;. It is also one very good app. It supports templates, there is few options when it comes to themes, it also has plugin support. I used joplin for a good amount of time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it because it has nothing interesting about it. It is opensource and by deafult does not sync to any cloud, (I think they have a paid plan now that lets you to sunc to their cloud). Even though their desktop app was decent
android app sucked. The UI looks so outdated, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all the features that the desktop version has. Android app is also not very smooth. It has the ability to sync to dropbox but the sync is so slow. And if you have enabled end to end encryption through the settings, good luck getting it working properly. Keep in mind that most problems I had with this app is in their android app, beacuse thats what I used to use to write my journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;obsidian&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; is the current app I am using. I absolutely love this app. It uses normal markdown files for each and every note, you can create normal folders inside obsidian and it would show the folders. Because each and individual notes are just simple .md files you can open them using any kind of text editor you prefer. Right now I am using Vim to edit this text. Obsidian is not open source but it can work offline, only time it needs to connect to the internet
is when downloading themes or plugins. Yes it supports themes, and I am pretty sure you can add your own css to obsidian. It also has template feature inbuilt, you can make it even more powerful with plugins. You can link your notes to another notes(Just like Roam Research, but you can only link a particular note and not a paragraph), and you can view a graph view which shows which note is linked with which. It is useful for me in so many cases, and not a lot of apps does that.
Everything is offline in obsidain by default, which may sound like a drawback if you want to sync your data with multiple devices, but it is not. Sure it is not as straightforward as installing an app and logging in, but you can make it work. I personally use DropBox (I would move to nextcloud once I get my nextcloud server running on raspberry pi) to sync my files. In linux and windows you can use the official dropbox app to sync the obsidian folder, and on Android you can use AutoSync
to sync to dropbox.
Obsidian can be very powerful if you want it to be, but it can be simple too. Third party plugins can extend the functionality of the app. &lt;em&gt;Plugins are also supported by their android app!!! How cool is that?&lt;/em&gt;
Obsidian is very good at what it does. But by no means it is perfect. It is bit tricky to set up sync on your devices,(like I have mentioned above) and even if you are able to set it up properly, you might get conflicts. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me because I am used to it at this point but I can see how this would make others annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There  is so many things an app needs to get right before I would use it for long, and yes I may not be the &amp;lsquo;general user&amp;rsquo;, So if you use any of the apps from above tell me what made you stick with it?
I am happy with obsidian as of now and not planning to switch anytime soon. Maybe someday when I learn vim or emacs enough to make obsidian obselete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was last updated on: 27/04/2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Journaling Is Better Than Physical Journaling</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/digital-journaling-is-better-than-physical-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:18:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/digital-journaling-is-better-than-physical-journaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy is better on digital Journalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More customisable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less bulky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to write&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search and Reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;better-privacy&#34;&gt;Better Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A daily journal is probably going to be one of the most private thing in your life. Because I know for a fact that, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how close you are to me I&amp;rsquo;m never going to share my journal with anyone but me.
If you are able to write digitally right way then it is very much possible to have greater privacy than that you&amp;rsquo;d get in physical journal. If you dont live alone, then its possible they can sneak into your journal. Even if I trust that person completely I&amp;rsquo;ll still be more comfortable knowing that he/she cannot access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easy-to-backup&#34;&gt;Easy to backup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not seem like something that is necessary for you, but for me backups are most important part of a journal. If I cannot read my journal entries 10-20 years into the future, then why bother writting it in the first place? Journals are sonething that I want to keep till the day I die.
You might argue that paper will last longer than lets say your hdd or any kind of digital storage, and you are right. But the problem is that in paper it is harder to copy, and maintain. You would to worry about pages turning yellow, different types of insects harming the paper, or worse some kind of disaster happening (like fire, water etc) and ruining your paper. You would be lose everything at once. Yes sure if you want to go to the extra mile you can make a xerox copy of your journals and it would medigate this problem. But it would easily get expensive as time goes on.&lt;br&gt;
On the other hand if you write digitally it would be so much easier to make backups of your journal. You can copy the containing folder and back it up somewhere else. Or if you are using something like &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Notion&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Evernote&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they all have some kind of export method. (You should not be using any writting app anyway which does not let you export your data easily.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;customization&#34;&gt;Customization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is theoratically no limit to how you would customise your journal. If you do not like a certain program you can always move to another, if you are still not satisfied to all the options you can write your own, well it would take time, but it is possible. Or you can use simple markdown files. With any text editors, let it be simple notepad or vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;less-bulky&#34;&gt;Less Bulky&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital journals are less bulky, you do not need any significant extra space at your home for digital journals. I have my journals from 2018 written digitally and they are just a few megabytes. Granted I do not write everyday and do not include much medias, (they are mostly plain texts with little bit of formatting here and there), it is still very little amount of files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easier-to-write&#34;&gt;Easier to write&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is significantly easier to write on keyboard than to use pen or paper. There is usually significant speed benifits, and automation, which I&amp;rsquo;ll explain on next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can automate things in your digital journal. If you are someone like me who likes to answer questions in form of Journal (ex: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;What did you do today?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;), you can make a template of your writting software so that everyday when you open your journal you start from your template instead starting form a blank page. Yes theoritically you can do the same on physical paper too, but it is easier digitally, and much much more advanced. I shall write a blog post about it someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ability-to-search-and-reference-back&#34;&gt;Ability to search and reference back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its easier to search a page or a mention of a specific thing on your journal. If you wrie digitally.
You can also reference back your old journals if necessary easily. For example you can have a page that would contain all the days where youn done something X, you can reference that page each time you do the X. I&amp;rsquo;ts bit advanced  stuff, but yes it would be helpful when you look back at the year or the decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical form of journaling has its advantages there is no doubt about that, but personally I prefer Digital ones. The beauty of digital journalism is that it can be as much complex as you want it to be, it can perfectly as you like it. Given that you are comfortable giving your time and energy to it. If you want a place to dump your brain and trying to lower your screen on time, then maybe you would be better off with physical ones, but for most people I think digital journal is much better than physical ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to say about this post, you can email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Wm</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/why-i-love-wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:13:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/why-i-love-wm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WM stands for window manager. It is a alternative to using full blown desktop environment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/window_manager&#34;&gt;More info on ArchWiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently started using WM, first i3 now on openbox. And absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are someone who is used to use normal desktop environment like gnome, kde, xfce or any other &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/desktop_environment&#34;&gt;DE (Desktop Environment)&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest to try out WM.You can start with anyone of those window manager you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with. Setting up wm is easy on fresh arch install so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-can-do-everything-using-keyboard-shortcuts&#34;&gt;You can do everything using keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening windows, closing windows, moving to different workspaces etc, can be done using keyboard shortcuts. It took me few days to get used to use keyboard shortcuts but now i can say it&amp;rsquo;s miles better than using mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-window-doesnt-cover-another&#34;&gt;One window doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover another&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t (by default), and why the hell would you want to keep one window on top of another?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;easily-customizable&#34;&gt;Easily customizable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I open up documentation in one workspace and vim with config file opened in another workspace. Changing everything is as easy as editing a text file. Documentations are mostly gets the job done, but if still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work one quick brave Search or youtube search does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loading-others-configuration&#34;&gt;Loading other&amp;rsquo;s configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna configure everything by myself, so I&amp;rsquo;d go &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/unixporn&#34;&gt;r/unixporn&lt;/a&gt; and load other&amp;rsquo;s configuration. And  &lt;em&gt;voilà&lt;/em&gt; its done. Well in reality I still have to open the config file and tweak here and there, but it&amp;rsquo;s usually &amp;rsquo;less time consuming&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forces-you-to-use-the-terminal&#34;&gt;Forces you to use the terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty new when it comes to Linux. Although terminal doesn&amp;rsquo;t scare me anymore, I sometimes still think using terminal is hard. Using a wm forces me to use terminal when possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;texts--icons&#34;&gt;Texts &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; Icons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been a fan of icons, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer simple texts over icons any day. A window manager normally doesn&amp;rsquo;t have icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-minimal-less-distracting-more-productive&#34;&gt;Its minimal, less distracting, more productive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t spend any time trying to arrange my opened tabs. (Suck on that Windows users) I&amp;rsquo;d open a programme because I want to open it, not because I was sitting mindlessly and getting bored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;elitism-feeling&#34;&gt;Elitism Feeling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes with the OS, if you&amp;rsquo;re a Linux user you know what I&amp;rsquo;m taking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still not convinced, I&amp;rsquo;ll suggest you give it a try, take a break from conventional way of managing windows and embrace the new. You can always go back to doing things your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS:&lt;/strong&gt;  I use Arch BTW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have something to say about this post, mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:blackpirate101@protonmail.com&#34;&gt;blackpirate101@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can click above or copy the email address from below.
&lt;code&gt;blackpirate101@protonmail.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextdns Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/nextdns-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 14:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/nextdns-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-dns&#34;&gt;What is DNS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Domain Name System is a hierarchical and decentralized naming system for computers, services, or other resources connected to the Internet or a private network. It associates various information with domain names assigned to each of the participating entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-nextdns&#34;&gt;What is NextDNS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is a dns service which lets you block sites at dns level. That means it can block ads and trackers. Which is the main selling point of this service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/img/nextdns-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;nextdns-logo&#34;&gt;
In simpler words it&amp;rsquo;s phone book of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using NextDNS for almost few months now. Yes I&amp;rsquo;ve been using their free plan. Which is more than enough for me. My experience with NextDNS is very positive. Once I set it up and did all the testing it never disappointed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;convenient&#34;&gt;Convenient&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is pretty convinient way to block ads. In privacy section there&amp;rsquo;s option to add well known adblocker blocklist. And it&amp;rsquo;s as easy it gets. After setting up your configuration you can easily change your dns setings in your operating system.
For more setup guide you can scroll down on their website and check their guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-time-setup&#34;&gt;First Time Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up for the first time is easy, but it night be a bit hard for non techie people. At first I was also having trouble finding out how to whitelist certain site. Also if you select all the adblock filters you might have some issues on certain sites. For example in my case my youtube app wasn&amp;rsquo;t recording history. Then I had to disable few adblock list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know NextDNS is pretty secure. They had option for 2step verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy&#34;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default privacy settings are crappy on NextDNS. But the good thing is that they let you change the default settings. By default it logs everything. I recommend you to disable logs and clear logs right now if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it already. Also NextDNS requires an email adress which you can easily fake using temp mail or alias.
In NextDNS you can link IP. Which is not good for privacy so wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using that feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS is feature packed. It&amp;rsquo;s like having your own pi hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pi-hole or Pihole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole and optionally a DHCP server, intended for use on a private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In NextDNS you can add different types of blocklist to block ads and trackers. Sadly they won&amp;rsquo;t allow you to choose to add your own blacklist. But in Denylist you can choose to block certain domain but sadly it won&amp;rsquo;t be possible to block a lot of domains at once.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.blackpiratex.com/img/nextdns-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;features&#34;&gt;
Their parental control feature is also awesome. It lets you block popular social media apps and websites in single click. Also there&amp;rsquo;s an option for recreation time which will allow those blocked sites for certain periods of time on certain days of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recreation time: Set a period for each day of the week during which some of the websites, apps, games or categories above will not be blocked — e.g. allow Facebook on Mondays and Tuesdays between 6pm and 8pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also turn on safesearch by default, block age restricted videos on youtube and block bypass methods like vpn. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how effective they&amp;rsquo;re, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have the option.
In analytics section you can see the analytics of that dns. Keep in mind that it only works if you have turned on logs.
NextDNS works on different types of DNS protocol like DNS over HTTPS, DNS over TLS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pricing&#34;&gt;Pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS free version is enough for me, (it gives you 300k dns queries) and also be enough for most people. But they also have paid plans which is a bit expensive where I live. Overall I&amp;rsquo;ll say it&amp;rsquo;s good for most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s looking for dns based adblocking solution NextDNS should be good enough for most of the people. Its convinient to set up (usually takes few mins), easy to manage and their free plan is actually useable. But for people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to trust a central company for all their internet traffic pi hole would be the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
