<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biology on Blog By BlackPirateX</title>
    <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biology on Blog By BlackPirateX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>BlackPirateX</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:06:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sexual Reproduction in Flowering Plants</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/sexual-reproduction-in-flowering-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/sexual-reproduction-in-flowering-plants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pre-fertilisation-events-and-structures&#34;&gt;Pre-Fertilisation Events and Structures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several hormonal and structural changes happen which lead to the differentiation and further devlopment of &lt;strong&gt;floral primordium&lt;/strong&gt; before flower in seen on a plant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inflorecences are formed which bears the floral bud and then the flowers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structures of a flower&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Androecium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the male reproductive organ of the flower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Androecium consists of &lt;strong&gt;stamens&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number and length of stamens are variable in different species.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stamen has two parts.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anther&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the bilobed structure at the terminal of the stamen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;filament&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the long and slender stalk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gynoecium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the female reproductive organ of the flower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It consists of pistil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If gynoecium consists of one pistil it is called &lt;strong&gt;monocarpellary&lt;/strong&gt;. If it consists of more than one then it is called &lt;strong&gt;multicarpellary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each pistil consists of three structures.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stigma&lt;/strong&gt; → It is where the pollen grains are landed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Style&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the long slender part beneath the stigma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ovary&lt;/strong&gt; → It is the basal bulged part.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the ovary there is &lt;strong&gt;ovarian cavity (locule).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;placenta is located in the ovarian cavity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Megasporongia&lt;/strong&gt; arise from the placenta. Which are commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Ovules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of ovules in an ovary can be &lt;strong&gt;one(wheat, paddy, mango)&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;multiple (papaya, water melon, orchids)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;stamen-microsporongium-and-pollen-grain&#34;&gt;Stamen, Microsporongium and pollen Grain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A typical angiosperm stamen is &lt;strong&gt;bilobed and dithecous&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A longitudinal groove runs lengthwise seperating the theca.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The anther is a &lt;strong&gt;tetragonial structure consisting four microsporongia in each four corners&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsporongium&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsporongium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It devlops further to make pollen sacs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are packed with pollen grains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In transverse section a typical microsporongia appears to be &lt;strong&gt;near circular in outline&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a four layer of walls srrounding it. From outside to inside it those are
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epidermis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endothecium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;middle layer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tapetum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outermost three layers (epidermis, endothecium, middle layer) helps in protection and dehiscence of anther to release the pollen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tapetum nourishes the pollen grains&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tapetum has &lt;strong&gt;dense cytoplasm and usually have more than one neucleus&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When anther is young compactly arranged homogenous tissues occupies the middle of the microsporongium, these cells are called &lt;strong&gt;sporogenous tissue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsporogenesis&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsporogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each microsporongium has lots of microspore mother cells/pollen mother cell (MMC/PMC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each cells of the sporongenous tissue undergo miotic division to form four cells which together are called Microspore Trtrad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the anther dehydrates and matures they disassociate from each other and each make pollen grain or microspore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pollen-grain&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pollen Grain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each pollen grains are male gametophyte.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the yellowish powdery thing that sticks on your finger when you touch the anther of hibbiscus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollen grains are &lt;strong&gt;generally spherical, and has a diameter of about 25-50 micrometers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has has prominent two layered wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the outermost layer of the pollen grain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is made up of &lt;strong&gt;sporopollenin which is a fatty substance.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is one of the most resistant organic material known. It can withstand high temparature and acid and alkali. No engyme can degrade sporopollenin so far known.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
3. It has prominent &lt;strong&gt;apertures which which are called germ pores&lt;/strong&gt;, where sporopollenin is absent.
4. germ pores are required for fertilisation.
5. Pollen grains are &lt;strong&gt;well preserved as fossils because of this sporopollenin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intine&lt;/strong&gt;
1. It is under the extine.
2. It is a thin continious layer &lt;strong&gt;made up of cellulose and pectin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When pollen grains mature it contains two cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vegitative Cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is bigger in size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has &lt;strong&gt;abundunt food reserve&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necleus is irregularly shaped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative Cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is smaller in size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spindle shaped&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dense cytoplasm and a necleus&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollen grains &lt;strong&gt;can cause allergic reactions, leading to chronic repiratory disorder like, asthma, bronchitis etc&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parthenium or carrot grass that came into india as a contaminent with imported wheat, is cause of pollen allergy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Reproduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/human-reproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 20:23:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/human-reproduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;male-reproductive-organ&#34;&gt;Male Reproductive Organ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male reproductive organs consists of testes, accesssory glands, glands and external genetitalia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male reproductive system is located in pelvic region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one pair of testes which is situated outside the human body within a pouch called scrotum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrotum has lower temparature than the body (2-2.5 degree celcius less)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This lower temparature is necessuary for spermatogenesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testis is oval in shape 4-5cm in length and 2-3 cm in width.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testes has 250 compartments which are called testicular lobules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each testicular lobules contains 2-3 seminiferous tubules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seminiferous tubules has two types of cells
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;germ cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sertoli cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germ cells undergo miotic divisions to produce sperms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sertoli cells mostly provide nutritions to germ cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the region outside the seminiferous tubules is called interstitial space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is full with blood vessels and cells found here are called interstitial cells or &lt;strong&gt;Laydig Cells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laydig cells secrete and synthesis testicular hormones called androgens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure-of-male-reproductive-accessory-ducts&#34;&gt;Structure of Male reproductive accessory ducts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seminiferous tubules opens into rete testis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rete testis opens into &lt;strong&gt;Vasa Efferentia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vasa Efferentia opens into &lt;strong&gt;Epididymis&lt;/strong&gt; which is located at the posterior of the testes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epididymis opens into &lt;strong&gt;Vasa Deferens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasa Deferens&lt;/strong&gt; ascends to the abdomen and loops over the urinary bladder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It recieves a duct from seminal vesicle and opens into urethra as ejaculatory duct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Urethra originates from urinary bladder and ends in the external opening of penis called &lt;strong&gt;Urethral meatus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penis is external genitilia of male, it is made up of special tissue which helps in erection for insemination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enlarged end of the penis is called glans penis and it is covered by foreskin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Male accessory glands include &lt;strong&gt;paired seminal vesicle&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;one prostate gland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;a pair of bulbourethral glands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secretions of these makes &lt;strong&gt;Seminal plasma&lt;/strong&gt; which is rich in &lt;strong&gt;fructose, calcium.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-female-reproductive-system&#34;&gt;The Female Reproductive System&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The feamle reproductive system consists of &lt;strong&gt;a pair of ovaries,  a pair of oviducts (fallopian tubes), utereus, cervix, vagina, and external genetilia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ovaries are located two sides of the utereus of lower abdomen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ovaries forms ovum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fallopian tubes extends from the periphery of the ovary to the utereus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fallopian tubes are 10-12 cm long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The funnel shaped thing near ovaries are called &lt;strong&gt;Infundibulum&lt;/strong&gt; which has finger-like projections called &lt;strong&gt;fimbrie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The part after infundibulum is called ampulla, it is wider, (this is the place where fertilisation takes place.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The part after ampulla is called isthmus, which connects to the utereus by a narrow lumen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus is called womb. It is shaped as inverted pear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has ligaments attacted to the pelvic region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus opens into vagina by a narrow cervix. i&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cavity of the cervix is called cervical canal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The uterus has three layers.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permetruim&lt;/strong&gt; - External thin membrenous tissue layer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myometrium&lt;/strong&gt; - middle thick layer of smooth muscles, exibits strong contractions during childbirth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endometrium&lt;/strong&gt; - inner glandular layer, it undergoes cyclical changes during menstrual cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Female external genitilia consists of &lt;strong&gt;mons pubis, labia majora, labia minora, clitoris, hymen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mons pubis&lt;/strong&gt; is a coushion of fatty tissue covered by skin and pubic hair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;labia majora&lt;/strong&gt; is a fleshy folds of tissue that extends from down the mons pubis and surround the vaginal opening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;labia minora&lt;/strong&gt; is under the labia majora.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clitoris&lt;/strong&gt; is a finger like structure which is located between the joints of two labia minora.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes vagina opening is partially covered by a membrane called &lt;strong&gt;hymen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hymen gets broken during the first intercourse (coitus), but it can also be broken by sudden fall or jolt, or by some sports like horseback riding, cycling etc, or by insertion of vaginal tampon etc. This is why it is not a reliable indicator of virginity or sexual experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;females have two mammary glands, which are called breasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these glands contains glandular tissue and variable amount of fat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the grandular tissue of each breasts is divided into &lt;strong&gt;15-20 mammary lobes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mammary lobes contains clusters of cells called &lt;strong&gt;alveoli&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alveoli&lt;/strong&gt; secretes milk, which is stored inside the cavity (lumen) of alveoli.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alveoli opens into &lt;strong&gt;mammary tubules&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tubules from each lobe gets together and forms &lt;strong&gt;mammary duct.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiple mammary ducts joins the wider mammary ampulla which is connected to the &lt;strong&gt;lactiferous duct&lt;/strong&gt; through which milk is sucked out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
