<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Blog By BlackPirateX</title>
    <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Blog By BlackPirateX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>BlackPirateX</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:08:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.blackpiratex.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Search for Perfect Daily Journal App</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:08:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/in-search-for-perfect-daily-journal-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be considered a viable app for my Daily Journal needs it must have following charateristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either end to end encrypted if the app is cloud based or data stays locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross platform. Including Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy way to export for personal backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of lack of privacy at my home, I had moved away from physical pen and paper diaries and moved completely to digital. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to hide something online than trying to hide at my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evernote&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very begining, circa 2017, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; Evernote was good back then. The 60mb that you get in free tier of evernote was more than enough for text based notes. I created a Notebook and used to add the date as title. It wasnt perfect. Writting date each and every day as note title is a tedious task. The search continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-unknown-app&#34;&gt;Some Unknown App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an app from playstore. I dont remember the name.  It was paid but i got it on a deal. Didn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anything. It was okay. Like not much features. Your data is stored locally. Although it had option to sync to dropbox. I used the sync feature. Sadly I dont think the app is alive. I maybe able to find it if I scroll back to my google play purchase history, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have that much patience. Unfortunately all the entries from that app is gone. I dont remember the droobox
account either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daybook&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next app that I used was &lt;a href=&#34;https://daybook.app&#34;&gt;Daybook&lt;/a&gt; , it was very minimal and decent app. It had lots of feature but free version was kinda limited. Still the UI and simplicity was the reason for using that app. But at the end one thing that put me off was their privacy policy. It was neither end to encrypted nor it had good privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notion&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; and started to love it. Notion had so many great features that I loved. Ability to make templates was one of them. Notion also supports basic markdown.  I remember using notion for like two months before the problems starts to appear.
Notion was online only, that means I cannot write my daily journal if my wifi was off. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen that often, but it was a possibility. Also if I go outside for few days, there would be no gurantee if I would be able to connect to the internet. It also bothered me that notion android app was basically a web app. Which means it was laggy, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel as smooth as native app.  The last thing that made me switch to Standard Notes was bad security and
privacy. Notion also is not end to end encrypted. They don&amp;rsquo;t even offer 2 step verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standard-notes&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://standardnotes.com&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/a&gt; was very good. I used their free version only, but still it was better than all previous apps that I have used. Security and privacy is great. They use end to end encryprion, and yes you cannot recover your password if you have lost it. They had apps for all the platforms. You can lock any particular note with another pin. It has theming support. If you get their premium version you&amp;rsquo;d get access to extensions which extends it&amp;rsquo;s
functionality.  I used it for a very long time before considering to switch.
Their free version is just plain text, nothing else. Sure you can use community made extensions to get markdown editors or different themes, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good. There were also no support for images, I  do not know if images support was avilable on paid plans or not. There were no support for templates. Themes are quite a bit limited on free version. These were the main reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t stick with standard notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joplin&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I was bored I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;. It is also one very good app. It supports templates, there is few options when it comes to themes, it also has plugin support. I used joplin for a good amount of time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it because it has nothing interesting about it. It is opensource and by deafult does not sync to any cloud, (I think they have a paid plan now that lets you to sunc to their cloud). Even though their desktop app was decent
android app sucked. The UI looks so outdated, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all the features that the desktop version has. Android app is also not very smooth. It has the ability to sync to dropbox but the sync is so slow. And if you have enabled end to end encryption through the settings, good luck getting it working properly. Keep in mind that most problems I had with this app is in their android app, beacuse thats what I used to use to write my journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;obsidian&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; is the current app I am using. I absolutely love this app. It uses normal markdown files for each and every note, you can create normal folders inside obsidian and it would show the folders. Because each and individual notes are just simple .md files you can open them using any kind of text editor you prefer. Right now I am using Vim to edit this text. Obsidian is not open source but it can work offline, only time it needs to connect to the internet
is when downloading themes or plugins. Yes it supports themes, and I am pretty sure you can add your own css to obsidian. It also has template feature inbuilt, you can make it even more powerful with plugins. You can link your notes to another notes(Just like Roam Research, but you can only link a particular note and not a paragraph), and you can view a graph view which shows which note is linked with which. It is useful for me in so many cases, and not a lot of apps does that.
Everything is offline in obsidain by default, which may sound like a drawback if you want to sync your data with multiple devices, but it is not. Sure it is not as straightforward as installing an app and logging in, but you can make it work. I personally use DropBox (I would move to nextcloud once I get my nextcloud server running on raspberry pi) to sync my files. In linux and windows you can use the official dropbox app to sync the obsidian folder, and on Android you can use AutoSync
to sync to dropbox.
Obsidian can be very powerful if you want it to be, but it can be simple too. Third party plugins can extend the functionality of the app. &lt;em&gt;Plugins are also supported by their android app!!! How cool is that?&lt;/em&gt;
Obsidian is very good at what it does. But by no means it is perfect. It is bit tricky to set up sync on your devices,(like I have mentioned above) and even if you are able to set it up properly, you might get conflicts. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me because I am used to it at this point but I can see how this would make others annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There  is so many things an app needs to get right before I would use it for long, and yes I may not be the &amp;lsquo;general user&amp;rsquo;, So if you use any of the apps from above tell me what made you stick with it?
I am happy with obsidian as of now and not planning to switch anytime soon. Maybe someday when I learn vim or emacs enough to make obsidian obselete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was last updated on: 27/04/2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Various Password Managers</title>
      <link>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/my-experience-with-various-password-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 18:53:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.blackpiratex.com/posts/my-experience-with-various-password-managers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years i have used many password managers. One of the biggest reasons I started using a password manager is not because of the security but rather I wanted a quick way to type my passwords. Also its easy for me to loose track of the websites I have signed up for. Now you may ask why I didn&amp;rsquo;t use something like password manager built in most modern web browser? Well the answer to that question is I wanted all my passwords to sync to different browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting I want to clear some things first. This review is based on my overall experience. I have only android devices and windows and linux. Your mileage may vary if you are on different devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lastpass-websitehttpslastpasscom&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LastPass&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros -&amp;gt; There is seriously none. Only reason to use it would be you&amp;rsquo;re into their ecosystem and can&amp;rsquo;t get out, or you have to use it for work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android app is terrible. The UI looks outdated. Android app is filled with trackers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has very serious security flaws throughout the years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LastPass#Security_issues&#34;&gt;More Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free version is unusable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot export your 2fa seeds if you ever plan to move to a new password manager. (Its necessary feature to have if you are planning to future proof your passwords or 2fa seeds.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitwarden-websitehttpsbitwardencom&#34;&gt;Bitwarden: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt; There is lot to love in Bitwarden.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security is flawless. Their apps are open source, You can self host your own instance if you want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy is also top notch. Android apps don&amp;rsquo;t contain any kind of trackers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has wide range of supported devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably the best free version of all the password managers. You would have to pay only if you need document support or want to generate TOTP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons: These might sound like nitpicking.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t like the android app ui. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel modern. It isn&amp;rsquo;t laggy but feels sluggish.&lt;/del&gt;  Update 29/04/2022: I am not bothered by it now, but yes sometimes Bitwarden lags while trying to autofill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their premium version is only 10$ per year, yes its hella cheap, but not in devloping countries. I wish they did regional pricing (I would definitely pay for it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to have an option where I can upload the encrypted data to a cloud drive. Its like self hosting only the data. (1password and enpass can do this.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of document support in free version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1password-websitehttps1passwordcom&#34;&gt;1password: &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1.  If you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay for a password manager this can be a great choice.
2. Absolutely a lot of features that you might find useful. For example password history, ability to add any custom field and section to store different types of information.
3. You can choose to store all the encrypted data to your own choice of cloud storage, like dropbox or google drive.
4. There&amp;rsquo;s no trackers in android apps and windows apps.
5. Ability to have multiple vaults,  but Enpass&amp;rsquo;s implementation is better.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot upload documents if you choose to store passwords by yourself (kinda like self hosting but not really) I mean one of the main reason to self host is that you can get document storage as much as you need. Even dropbox free gives 2GB (which can be increased to 18GB) which is much better than 1GB storage that you get in your subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not open source at all. But they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any data breach or anything that I can find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enpass-websitehttpswwwenpassio&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enpass:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.enpass.io/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;
1. Extremely feature rich. It has everything you can ask for in a password manager.
2. It works without any account or without internet connection at all. Although you&amp;rsquo;ll need internet connection to sync across devices which is optional.
3. Ability to have multiple vaults, (1Password has this feature too but in my opinion enpass&amp;rsquo;s implementation is better.)
4. There&amp;rsquo;s no limit of how many data (passwords, documents, notes) you can store.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All apps are closed source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dashlane-websitehttpswwwdashlanecom&#34;&gt;Dashlane: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dashlane.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:-&lt;/strong&gt;
1. The user interface is very simple.
2. Beginner-normie Friendly
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:-&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing is open source. Privacy is meh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features are very limited. Last time I checked they didn&amp;rsquo;t even had option for custom fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Desktop Application, You&amp;rsquo;ll have to use their web app or extension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free version doesn&amp;rsquo;t sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keepass-websitehttpskeepassinfo&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keepass:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://keepass.info/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used keepass only briefly, I have multiple devices, so I need to access my keepass file everywhere, which is not an easy task to do with keepass.
I know that it is achieveable, but it sure is not as straightforward as something like bitwarden or enpass. I tried using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keepassdx.com/&#34;&gt;KeePassDX&lt;/a&gt; with dropbox sync, and it gets conflict so often. So it gets pretty unuseable. I may start using it again once I figure out how to get sync working properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the password managers I have used my favourite would be Bitwarden, Enpass is a close second. If closed source stuff does not bother you and you want extra fatures, you can use Enpass or 1Password. I personally would prefer enpass more than 1Password. Currently as of April 2022 I aPeriod.m using Bitwarden. Earlier I was using enpass, only reason I moved away from enpass is beacuse of it&amp;rsquo;s closed source nature. For something as important as password manager, it should be open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have anything to comment about this post, you can mail me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:comments@blackpiratex.com&#34;&gt;comments@blackpiratex.com&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll be waiting for your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
